<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Journal on paregis.me - just another personal projects website</title><link>/categories/journal/</link><description>Recent content in Journal on paregis.me - just another personal projects website</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>All rights preserved.</copyright><lastBuildDate>Wed, 01 May 2019 00:00:00 -0500</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/categories/journal/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Dynamic Self Reconfiguration of Unmanned Aerial Vehicles to Serve Overloaded Hotspot Cells</title><link>/publications/dynamic-self-reconfiguration-of-unmanned-aerial-vehicles-to-serve-overloaded-hotspot-cells/</link><pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2019 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate><guid>/publications/dynamic-self-reconfiguration-of-unmanned-aerial-vehicles-to-serve-overloaded-hotspot-cells/</guid><description>Abstract Unmanned Aerial Vehicle (UAV) networks can provide wireless coverage to users when cellular infrastructure is unavailable. Each UAV covers a circular area, called a hotspot cell, and serves the users in it. Natural disasters can cause unpredictable mobility of users, randomly overloading some cells, called hot zones, for different time intervals. Along with an efficient initial deployment, this paper presents a two-fold approach to handle hot zones. First, the loads in overlapped sections are redistributed to neighbors.</description><content>&lt;h2 id="abstract">Abstract&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Unmanned Aerial Vehicle (UAV) networks can provide wireless coverage to users when cellular infrastructure is unavailable. Each UAV covers a circular area, called a hotspot cell, and serves the users in it. Natural disasters can cause unpredictable mobility of users, randomly overloading some cells, called hot zones, for different time intervals. Along with an efficient initial deployment, this paper presents a two-fold approach to handle hot zones. First, the loads in overlapped sections are redistributed to neighbors. Second, a distributed algorithm is run that dynamically re-positions the least number of UAVs to serve the maximum possible users. Additionally, to balance the user demand and supply of wireless coverage, adjacent UAVs are allowed to swap their positions. Simulation results show improvement in the network performance using the parameters: packet delivery ratio, data served per unit of depleted energy, service discontinuity time, and the total amount of data served.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="resources">Resources&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="resources/caee_19.pdf">Manuscript&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="bibtex">Bibtex&lt;/h2>
&lt;div class="highlight">&lt;pre tabindex="0" style="color:#f8f8f2;background-color:#272822;-moz-tab-size:4;-o-tab-size:4;tab-size:4;">&lt;code class="language-latex" data-lang="latex">&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span>@article{patra2019dynamic,
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span> title={Dynamic Self-Reconfiguration of Unmanned Aerial Vehicles to Serve Overloaded Hotspot Cells},
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span> author={Amar Nath Patra, Paulo Alexandre Regis, and Shamik Sengupta},
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span> year={2019},
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span> month={May},
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span> doi={10.1016/j.compeleceng.2019.02.014},
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span> journal={Elsevier Computers and Electrical Engineering},
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span>}
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;/code>&lt;/pre>&lt;/div></content></item><item><title>Distributed Allocation and Dynamic Reassignment of Channels in Uav Networks for Wireless Coverage</title><link>/publications/distributed-allocation-and-dynamic-reassignment-of-channels-in-uav-networks-for-wireless-coverage/</link><pubDate>Fri, 01 Mar 2019 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate><guid>/publications/distributed-allocation-and-dynamic-reassignment-of-channels-in-uav-networks-for-wireless-coverage/</guid><description>Abstract Providing wireless coverage to users using Unmanned Aerial Vehicles (UAVs) encounters two major challenges: deployment and channel allocation. To this end, solutions to both issues are proposed in this paper. An overloaded UAV attempts to acquire more channels by performing channel bonding/aggregation followed by requesting its chosen peers to move closer for load sharing. The proposed channel reallocation schemes minimize interference caused by channel reassignments, or change in network topology.</description><content>&lt;h2 id="abstract">Abstract&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Providing wireless coverage to users using Unmanned Aerial Vehicles (UAVs) encounters two major challenges: deployment and channel allocation. To this end, solutions to both issues are proposed in this paper. An overloaded UAV attempts to acquire more channels by performing channel bonding/aggregation followed by requesting its chosen peers to move closer for load sharing. The proposed channel reallocation schemes minimize interference caused by channel reassignments, or change in network topology. The simulation results show that when employing these schemes, more data is served with reduced discontinuous service time and efficient usage of limited battery power.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="resources">Resources&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="resources/pmc_19.pdf">Manuscript&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="bibtex">Bibtex&lt;/h2>
&lt;div class="highlight">&lt;pre tabindex="0" style="color:#f8f8f2;background-color:#272822;-moz-tab-size:4;-o-tab-size:4;tab-size:4;">&lt;code class="language-latex" data-lang="latex">&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span>@article{patra2019distributed,
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span> title={Distributed Allocation and Dynamic Reassignment of Channels in UAV Networks for Wireless Coverage},
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span> author={Amar Nath Patra, Paulo Alexandre Regis, and Shamik Sengupta},
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span> year={2019},
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span> month={March},
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span> doi={10.1016/j.pmcj.2019.02.005},
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span> journal={Elsevier Pervasive and Mobile Computing},
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span>}
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;/code>&lt;/pre>&lt;/div></content></item><item><title>Distributed Adaptive Beam Nulling to Survive Against Jamming in 3 D Uav Mesh Networks</title><link>/publications/distributed-adaptive-beam-nulling-to-survive-against-jamming-in-3-d-uav-mesh-networks/</link><pubDate>Fri, 01 Jun 2018 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate><guid>/publications/distributed-adaptive-beam-nulling-to-survive-against-jamming-in-3-d-uav-mesh-networks/</guid><description>Abstract In the future generation mission-centric tactical network, 3D UAV mesh network will play a crucial role for its several advantages. However, any adversarial node with the 3D movement capability poses a significant threat to these networks as the adversary can position itself to attack the crucial links. An adaptive beamnulling antenna is used to spatially filter out signal coming from a certain direction that can maintain the links active without requiring additional spectrum.</description><content>&lt;h2 id="abstract">Abstract&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>In the future generation mission-centric tactical network, 3D UAV mesh network will play a crucial role for its several advantages. However, any adversarial node with the 3D movement capability poses a significant threat to these networks as the adversary can position itself to attack the crucial links. An adaptive beamnulling antenna is used to spatially filter out signal coming from a certain direction that can maintain the links active without requiring additional spectrum. However, determining the beamnull region is very challenging for jammer with mobility. This paper presents a distributed mechanism where nodes measure the jammer’s direction in a discrete interval and determine the optimal beamnull for the next interval. Kalman filter based tracking mechanism is used to estimate the most likely trajectory of the jammer from noisy observation of the jammer’s position. A beam null border is determined by calculating confidence region of jammer’s current and next position estimates. An optimization goal is presented to determine the optimal beam null that minimizes the number of deactivated links while maximizing the higher value of confidence for keeping the jammer inside the null. The framework works in the physical layer and can work with any upper layer protocol. The survivability of a 3D mesh network with a mobile jammer is studied through simulation that validates an 96.65% reduction in the number of jammed nodes.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="resources">Resources&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="resources/comnet_18.pdf">Manuscript&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="bibtex">Bibtex&lt;/h2>
&lt;div class="highlight">&lt;pre tabindex="0" style="color:#f8f8f2;background-color:#272822;-moz-tab-size:4;-o-tab-size:4;tab-size:4;">&lt;code class="language-latex" data-lang="latex">&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span>@article{bhunia2018distributed,
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span> title={Distributed Adaptive Beam Nulling to Survive Against Jamming in 3D UAV Mesh Networks},
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span> author={Suman Bhunia, Paulo Alexandre Regis, and Shamik Sengupta},
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span> year={2018},
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span> month={June},
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span> doi={10.1016/j.comnet.2018.03.011},
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span> journal={Elsevier Computer Networks},
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span>}
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;/code>&lt;/pre>&lt;/div></content></item><item><title>Multi Hop Mobile Wireless Mesh Network Testbed Development and Measurements</title><link>/publications/multi-hop-mobile-wireless-mesh-network-testbed-development-and-measurements/</link><pubDate>Tue, 01 Aug 2017 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate><guid>/publications/multi-hop-mobile-wireless-mesh-network-testbed-development-and-measurements/</guid><description>Abstract Mesh networks are envisioned to play a major role in the future of Smart-Cities and Internet of Things technologies, and can be a great ally in executing mission-centric tasks like search and rescue, and assist first responders. In this paper, we demonstrate the feasibility of development of a mobile mesh network testbed with the help of commercial-off-the-shelf (COTS) components and perform measurement tests in an indoor environment. We used open-source software to enable the testbed, such as Linux as the operating system, and Optimized Link State Routing (OLSR) protocol to enable the wireless mesh network.</description><content>&lt;h2 id="abstract">Abstract&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Mesh networks are envisioned to play a major role in the future of Smart-Cities and Internet of Things technologies, and can be a great ally in executing mission-centric tasks like search and rescue, and assist first responders. In this paper, we demonstrate the feasibility of development of a mobile mesh network testbed with the help of commercial-off-the-shelf (COTS) components and perform measurement tests in an indoor environment. We used open-source software to enable the testbed, such as Linux as the operating system, and Optimized Link State Routing (OLSR) protocol to enable the wireless mesh network. The physical components include open-source hardware like Raspberry Pi computers, and mobility is enabled through the use of a mobile robot Pioneer 3. We evaluate the network in various scenarios, first establishing benchmark measurement in a stationary setup, and then comparing with a mobile variation.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="resources">Resources&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="resources/rroij_17.pdf">Manuscript&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="bibtex">Bibtex&lt;/h2>
&lt;div class="highlight">&lt;pre tabindex="0" style="color:#f8f8f2;background-color:#272822;-moz-tab-size:4;-o-tab-size:4;tab-size:4;">&lt;code class="language-latex" data-lang="latex">&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span>@article{regis2017multi-hop,
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span> title={Multi-hop Mobile Wireless Mesh Network Testbed Development and Measurements},
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span> author={Paulo Alexandre Regis, Cayler Miley, and Shamik Sengupta},
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span> year={2017},
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span> month={August},
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span> journal={IJIRCCE International Journal of Innovative Research in Computer and Communication Engineering},
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span>}
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;/code>&lt;/pre>&lt;/div></content></item><item><title>Adaptive Beam Nulling in Multihop Ad Hoc Networks Against a Jammer in Motion</title><link>/publications/adaptive-beam-nulling-in-multihop-ad-hoc-networks-against-a-jammer-in-motion/</link><pubDate>Tue, 01 Nov 2016 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate><guid>/publications/adaptive-beam-nulling-in-multihop-ad-hoc-networks-against-a-jammer-in-motion/</guid><description>Abstract In multihop ad hoc networks, a jammer can drastically disrupt the flow of information by intentionally interfering with links between a subset of nodes. The impact of such attacks can escalate when the jammer is moving. As a countermeasure for such attacks, adaptive beam-forming techniques can be employed for spatial filtering of the jamming signal. This paper investigates the performance of adaptive beam nulling as a mitigation technique against jamming attacks in multihop ad hoc networks.</description><content>&lt;h2 id="abstract">Abstract&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>In multihop ad hoc networks, a jammer can drastically disrupt the flow of information by intentionally interfering with links between a subset of nodes. The impact of such attacks can escalate when the jammer is moving. As a countermeasure for such attacks, adaptive beam-forming techniques can be employed for spatial filtering of the jamming signal. This paper investigates the performance of adaptive beam nulling as a mitigation technique against jamming attacks in multihop ad hoc networks. Considering a moving jammer, a distributed beam nulling framework is proposed. The framework uses periodic measurements of the RF environment to detect direction of arrival (DoA) of jamming signal and suppresses the signals arriving from the current and predicted locations of the jammer. Also, in the calculation of the nulled region, this framework considers and counters the effects of randomness in the mobility of the jammer, as well as errors in beam nulling and DoA measurements. Survivability of links and connectivity in such scenarios are studied by simulating various node distributions and different mobility patterns of the attacker. Also, the impact of errors in the estimation of DoA and beam-forming on the overall network performance is also examined. In comparison with an omnidirectional configuration, results indicate a 57.27% improvement in connectivity under jamming when the proposed framework is applied.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="resources">Resources&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="resources/comnet_16.pdf">Manuscript&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="bibtex">Bibtex&lt;/h2>
&lt;div class="highlight">&lt;pre tabindex="0" style="color:#f8f8f2;background-color:#272822;-moz-tab-size:4;-o-tab-size:4;tab-size:4;">&lt;code class="language-latex" data-lang="latex">&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span>@article{bhunia2016adaptive,
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span> title={Adaptive Beam Nulling in Multihop Ad Hoc Networks Against a Jammer in Motion},
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span> author={Suman Bhunia, Vahid Behzadan, Paulo Alexandre Regis, and Shamik Sengupta},
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span> year={2016},
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span> month={November},
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span> doi={10.1016/j.comnet.2016.06.030},
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span> journal={Elsevier Computer Networks},
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span>}
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;/code>&lt;/pre>&lt;/div></content></item></channel></rss>