<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Publications on paregis.me</title><link>/publications/</link><description>Recent content in Publications on paregis.me</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>All rights preserved.</copyright><lastBuildDate>Wed, 08 Jun 2022 14:30:04 -0500</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/publications/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Deep Learning Assisted Cross Layer Routing in Multi Hop Wireless Network</title><link>/publications/deep-learning-assisted-cross-layer-routing-in-multi-hop-wireless-network/</link><pubDate>Mon, 14 Jun 2021 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate><guid>/publications/deep-learning-assisted-cross-layer-routing-in-multi-hop-wireless-network/</guid><description>Abstract Wireless ad hoc networks rely on exchanging information among the nodes to find a feasible route between source and destination. Routing protocols require periodically flooding the entire system with the updated state of the network. Routing protocols define the rules and semantics of how this information is spread throughout the network and can be classified into proactive and reactive protocols, both of which eventually sends out control packets to the network.</description><content>&lt;h2 id="abstract">Abstract&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Wireless ad hoc networks rely on exchanging information among the nodes to find a feasible route between source and destination. Routing protocols require periodically flooding the entire system with the updated state of the network. Routing protocols define the rules and semantics of how this information is spread throughout the network and can be classified into proactive and reactive protocols, both of which eventually sends out control packets to the network. However, with the increase of the scale of the network, the amount of packets exchanged uses resources that could be otherwise used for application messages. In this paper, we explore the use of machine learning techniques to restrict the flooding radius of control packets. We define the problem objective as a regression problem and use neural networks to model it. The model can be used in networks that share similar attributes, suggesting that transfer learning can be used to re-purpose the initial model. The results show that using machine learning reduces the amount of resources used to maintain the network state up to date, which could be subsequently used to improve the overall performance of the networked system. We anticipate machine learning to be the starting point for more sophisticated models of cross-layer routing mechanisms.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="resources">Resources&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="resources/wfiot_21.pdf">Manuscript&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="bibtex">Bibtex&lt;/h2>
&lt;div class="highlight">&lt;pre tabindex="0" style="color:#f8f8f2;background-color:#272822;-moz-tab-size:4;-o-tab-size:4;tab-size:4;">&lt;code class="language-latex" data-lang="latex">&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span>@inproceedings{regis2021deep-learning,
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span> title={Deep-learning assisted Cross-Layer Routing in Multi-hop Wireless Network},
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span> author={Paulo Alexandre Regis, Suman Bhunia, Amar Nath Patra, and Shamik Sengupta},
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span> year={2021},
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span> publisher={IEEE},
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span> address={New Orleans, LA, USA},
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span> booktitle={None},
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span>}
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;/code>&lt;/pre>&lt;/div></content></item><item><title>Low Cost Wireless Testbed for Internet of Things Ad Hoc Networks Prototyping and Evaluation</title><link>/publications/low-cost-wireless-testbed-for-internet-of-things-ad-hoc-networks-prototyping-and-evaluation/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jun 2020 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate><guid>/publications/low-cost-wireless-testbed-for-internet-of-things-ad-hoc-networks-prototyping-and-evaluation/</guid><description>Abstract There is a distinct gap in IoT research between simulation and implementation of new networking protocols. While simulations allow fast validation of new ideas, it is not until implemented into a real system that a novel protocol gains tracking. We build an ad hoc network system to enable energy-aware protocol testing in real devices with reusable code. We demonstrate how to use low-cost components with open-source libraries to implement the system.</description><content>&lt;h2 id="abstract">Abstract&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>There is a distinct gap in IoT research between simulation and implementation of new networking protocols. While simulations allow fast validation of new ideas, it is not until implemented into a real system that a novel protocol gains tracking. We build an ad hoc network system to enable energy-aware protocol testing in real devices with reusable code. We demonstrate how to use low-cost components with open-source libraries to implement the system. We implemented models to allow the energy-awareness using a network simulator, and experiments to compare different routing protocols through indoor and outdoor experiments, showing the feasibility of the system.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="resources">Resources&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="resources/wfiot_20.pdf">Manuscript&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;div style="position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%; height: 0; overflow: hidden;">
&lt;iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/8ErHu8l7-bk" style="position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; border:0;" allowfullscreen title="Low Cost Wireless Testbed for Internet of Things Ad Hoc Networks Prototyping and Evaluation">&lt;/iframe>
&lt;/div>
&lt;h2 id="bibtex">Bibtex&lt;/h2>
&lt;div class="highlight">&lt;pre tabindex="0" style="color:#f8f8f2;background-color:#272822;-moz-tab-size:4;-o-tab-size:4;tab-size:4;">&lt;code class="language-latex" data-lang="latex">&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span>@inproceedings{regis2020low-cost,
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span> title={Low-cost wireless testbed for Internet of Things ad hoc networks prototyping and evaluation},
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span> author={Paulo Alexandre Regis, Amar Nath Patra, and Shamik Sengupta},
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span> year={2020},
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span> publisher={IEEE},
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span> address={New Orleans, LA, USA},
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span> booktitle={None},
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span>}
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;/code>&lt;/pre>&lt;/div></content></item><item><title>Optimal Uav Positioning for a Temporary Network Using an Iterative Genetic Algorithm</title><link>/publications/optimal-uav-positioning-for-a-temporary-network-using-an-iterative-genetic-algorithm/</link><pubDate>Fri, 01 May 2020 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate><guid>/publications/optimal-uav-positioning-for-a-temporary-network-using-an-iterative-genetic-algorithm/</guid><description>Abstract Efficient arrangement of UAVs in a swarm formation is essential to the functioning of the swarm as a temporary communication network. Such a network could assist in search and rescue efforts by providing first responders with a means of communication. We propose a user-friendly and effective system for calculating and visualizing an optimal layout of UAVs. An initial calculation to gather parameter information is followed by the proposed algorithm that generates an optimal solution.</description><content>&lt;h2 id="abstract">Abstract&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Efficient arrangement of UAVs in a swarm formation is essential to the functioning of the swarm as a temporary communication network. Such a network could assist in search and rescue efforts by providing first responders with a means of communication. We propose a user-friendly and effective system for calculating and visualizing an optimal layout of UAVs. An initial calculation to gather parameter information is followed by the proposed algorithm that generates an optimal solution. A visualization is displayed in an easy-to-comprehend manner after the proposed iterative genetic algorithm finds an optimal solution. The proposed system runs iteratively, adding UAV at each intermediate conclusion, until a solution is found. Information is passed between runs of the iterative genetic algorithm to reduce runtime and complexity. The results from testing show that the proposed algorithm yields optimal solutions more frequently than the k-means clustering algorithm. This system finds an optimal solution 80% of the time while k-means clustering is unable to find a solution when presented with a complex problem.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="resources">Resources&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="resources/wocc_20.pdf">Manuscript&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="bibtex">Bibtex&lt;/h2>
&lt;div class="highlight">&lt;pre tabindex="0" style="color:#f8f8f2;background-color:#272822;-moz-tab-size:4;-o-tab-size:4;tab-size:4;">&lt;code class="language-latex" data-lang="latex">&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span>@inproceedings{ceccarelli2020optimal,
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span> title={Optimal UAV Positioning for a Temporary Network Using an Iterative Genetic Algorithm},
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span> author={Nicholas Ceccarelli, Paulo Alexandre Regis, David Feil-Seifer, and Shamik Sengupta},
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span> year={2020},
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span> publisher={IEEE},
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span> address={Newark, NJ, USA},
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span> booktitle={2020 29th Wireless and Optical Communications Conference (WOCC)},
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span>}
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;/code>&lt;/pre>&lt;/div></content></item><item><title>Area Optimized Uav Swarm Network for Search and Rescue Operations</title><link>/publications/area-optimized-uav-swarm-network-for-search-and-rescue-operations/</link><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2020 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate><guid>/publications/area-optimized-uav-swarm-network-for-search-and-rescue-operations/</guid><description>Abstract Intelligent robot swarms are increasingly being explored as tools for search and rescue missions. Efficient path planning and robust communication networks are critical elements of completing missions. The focus of this research is to give unmanned aerial vehicles (UAVs) the ability to self-organize a mesh network that is optimized for area coverage. The UAVs will be able to read the communication strength between themselves and all the UAVs it is connected to using RSSI.</description><content>&lt;h2 id="abstract">Abstract&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Intelligent robot swarms are increasingly being explored as tools for search and rescue missions. Efficient path planning and robust communication networks are critical elements of completing missions. The focus of this research is to give unmanned aerial vehicles (UAVs) the ability to self-organize a mesh network that is optimized for area coverage. The UAVs will be able to read the communication strength between themselves and all the UAVs it is connected to using RSSI. The UAVs should be able to adjust their positioning closer to other UAVs if RSSI is below a threshold, and they should also maintain communication as a group if they move together along a search path. Our approach was to use Genetic Algorithms in a simulated environment to achieve multi-node exploration with emphasis on connectivity and swarm spread.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="resources">Resources&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="resources/ccwc_20.pdf">Manuscript&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="resources/ccwc_20.pptx">Presentation&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="bibtex">Bibtex&lt;/h2>
&lt;div class="highlight">&lt;pre tabindex="0" style="color:#f8f8f2;background-color:#272822;-moz-tab-size:4;-o-tab-size:4;tab-size:4;">&lt;code class="language-latex" data-lang="latex">&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span>@inproceedings{ruetten2020area-optimized,
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span> title={Area-Optimized UAV Swarm Network for Search and Rescue Operations},
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span> author={Laik Ruetten, Paulo Alexandre Regis, David Feil-Seifer, and Shamik Sengupta},
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span> year={2020},
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span> publisher={IEEE},
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span> address={Las Vegas, NV, USA},
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span> booktitle={2020 10th Annual Computing and Communication Workshop and Conference (CCWC)},
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span>}
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;/code>&lt;/pre>&lt;/div></content></item><item><title>Dynamic Self Reconfiguration of Unmanned Aerial Vehicles to Serve Overloaded Hotspot Cells</title><link>/publications/dynamic-self-reconfiguration-of-unmanned-aerial-vehicles-to-serve-overloaded-hotspot-cells/</link><pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2019 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate><guid>/publications/dynamic-self-reconfiguration-of-unmanned-aerial-vehicles-to-serve-overloaded-hotspot-cells/</guid><description>Abstract Unmanned Aerial Vehicle (UAV) networks can provide wireless coverage to users when cellular infrastructure is unavailable. Each UAV covers a circular area, called a hotspot cell, and serves the users in it. Natural disasters can cause unpredictable mobility of users, randomly overloading some cells, called hot zones, for different time intervals. Along with an efficient initial deployment, this paper presents a two-fold approach to handle hot zones. First, the loads in overlapped sections are redistributed to neighbors.</description><content>&lt;h2 id="abstract">Abstract&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Unmanned Aerial Vehicle (UAV) networks can provide wireless coverage to users when cellular infrastructure is unavailable. Each UAV covers a circular area, called a hotspot cell, and serves the users in it. Natural disasters can cause unpredictable mobility of users, randomly overloading some cells, called hot zones, for different time intervals. Along with an efficient initial deployment, this paper presents a two-fold approach to handle hot zones. First, the loads in overlapped sections are redistributed to neighbors. Second, a distributed algorithm is run that dynamically re-positions the least number of UAVs to serve the maximum possible users. Additionally, to balance the user demand and supply of wireless coverage, adjacent UAVs are allowed to swap their positions. Simulation results show improvement in the network performance using the parameters: packet delivery ratio, data served per unit of depleted energy, service discontinuity time, and the total amount of data served.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="resources">Resources&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="resources/caee_19.pdf">Manuscript&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="bibtex">Bibtex&lt;/h2>
&lt;div class="highlight">&lt;pre tabindex="0" style="color:#f8f8f2;background-color:#272822;-moz-tab-size:4;-o-tab-size:4;tab-size:4;">&lt;code class="language-latex" data-lang="latex">&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span>@article{patra2019dynamic,
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span> title={Dynamic Self-Reconfiguration of Unmanned Aerial Vehicles to Serve Overloaded Hotspot Cells},
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span> author={Amar Nath Patra, Paulo Alexandre Regis, and Shamik Sengupta},
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span> year={2019},
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span> month={May},
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span> doi={10.1016/j.compeleceng.2019.02.014},
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span> journal={Elsevier Computers and Electrical Engineering},
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span>}
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;/code>&lt;/pre>&lt;/div></content></item><item><title>Distributed Allocation and Dynamic Reassignment of Channels in Uav Networks for Wireless Coverage</title><link>/publications/distributed-allocation-and-dynamic-reassignment-of-channels-in-uav-networks-for-wireless-coverage/</link><pubDate>Fri, 01 Mar 2019 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate><guid>/publications/distributed-allocation-and-dynamic-reassignment-of-channels-in-uav-networks-for-wireless-coverage/</guid><description>Abstract Providing wireless coverage to users using Unmanned Aerial Vehicles (UAVs) encounters two major challenges: deployment and channel allocation. To this end, solutions to both issues are proposed in this paper. An overloaded UAV attempts to acquire more channels by performing channel bonding/aggregation followed by requesting its chosen peers to move closer for load sharing. The proposed channel reallocation schemes minimize interference caused by channel reassignments, or change in network topology.</description><content>&lt;h2 id="abstract">Abstract&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Providing wireless coverage to users using Unmanned Aerial Vehicles (UAVs) encounters two major challenges: deployment and channel allocation. To this end, solutions to both issues are proposed in this paper. An overloaded UAV attempts to acquire more channels by performing channel bonding/aggregation followed by requesting its chosen peers to move closer for load sharing. The proposed channel reallocation schemes minimize interference caused by channel reassignments, or change in network topology. The simulation results show that when employing these schemes, more data is served with reduced discontinuous service time and efficient usage of limited battery power.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="resources">Resources&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="resources/pmc_19.pdf">Manuscript&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="bibtex">Bibtex&lt;/h2>
&lt;div class="highlight">&lt;pre tabindex="0" style="color:#f8f8f2;background-color:#272822;-moz-tab-size:4;-o-tab-size:4;tab-size:4;">&lt;code class="language-latex" data-lang="latex">&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span>@article{patra2019distributed,
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span> title={Distributed Allocation and Dynamic Reassignment of Channels in UAV Networks for Wireless Coverage},
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span> author={Amar Nath Patra, Paulo Alexandre Regis, and Shamik Sengupta},
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span> year={2019},
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span> month={March},
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span> doi={10.1016/j.pmcj.2019.02.005},
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span> journal={Elsevier Pervasive and Mobile Computing},
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span>}
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;/code>&lt;/pre>&lt;/div></content></item><item><title>Search and Rescue Operations With Mesh Networked Robots</title><link>/publications/search-and-rescue-operations-with-mesh-networked-robots/</link><pubDate>Thu, 01 Nov 2018 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate><guid>/publications/search-and-rescue-operations-with-mesh-networked-robots/</guid><description>Abstract Efficient path planning and communication of multi-robot systems in the case of a search and rescue operation is a critical issue facing robotics disaster relief efforts. Ensuring all the nodes of a specialized robotic search team are within range, while also covering as much area as possible to guarantee efficient response time, is the goal of this paper. We propose a specialized search-and-rescue model based on a mesh network topology of aerial and ground robots.</description><content>&lt;h2 id="abstract">Abstract&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Efficient path planning and communication of multi-robot systems in the case of a search and rescue operation is a critical issue facing robotics disaster relief efforts. Ensuring all the nodes of a specialized robotic search team are within range, while also covering as much area as possible to guarantee efficient response time, is the goal of this paper. We propose a specialized search-and-rescue model based on a mesh network topology of aerial and ground robots. The proposed model is based on several methods. First, each robot determines its position relative to other robots within the system, using RSSI. Packets are then communicated to other robots in the system detailing important information regarding robot system status, status of the mission, and identification number. The results demonstrate the ability to determine multi-robot navigation with RSSI, allowing low computation costs and increased search-and-rescue time efficiency.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="resources">Resources&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="resources/uemcon_18.pdf">Manuscript&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="resources/uemcon_18.pptx">Presentation&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="bibtex">Bibtex&lt;/h2>
&lt;div class="highlight">&lt;pre tabindex="0" style="color:#f8f8f2;background-color:#272822;-moz-tab-size:4;-o-tab-size:4;tab-size:4;">&lt;code class="language-latex" data-lang="latex">&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span>@inproceedings{brodeur2018search,
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span> title={Search and Rescue Operations with Mesh Networked Robots},
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span> author={Tristan Brodeur, Paulo Alexandre Regis, David Feil-Seifer, and Shamik Sengupta},
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span> year={2018},
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span> publisher={IEEE},
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span> address={New York, NY, USA},
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span> booktitle={2018 9th IEEE Annual Ubiquitous Computing, Electronics &amp;amp; Mobile Communication Conference (UEMCON)},
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span>}
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;/code>&lt;/pre>&lt;/div></content></item><item><title>Unmanned Aerial Vehicles Positioning Scheme for First Responders in a Dynamic Area of Interest</title><link>/publications/unmanned-aerial-vehicles-positioning-scheme-for-first-responders-in-a-dynamic-area-of-interest/</link><pubDate>Wed, 01 Aug 2018 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate><guid>/publications/unmanned-aerial-vehicles-positioning-scheme-for-first-responders-in-a-dynamic-area-of-interest/</guid><description>Abstract In this paper, we explore the problem of finding the initial positions to deploy UAVs to provide service to ground personnel. In this work, we propose a greedy algorithm that finds a feasible solution that guarantees 100% coverage on any given map. We defined subareas of the map which do not need coverage as excluding zones. We considered both excluding zones and the connectivity constraints in the algorithm. By avoiding these zones and keeping all nodes connected to the network we can reduce the total number of UAVs needed to provide coverage without losing the communication capability.</description><content>&lt;h2 id="abstract">Abstract&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>In this paper, we explore the problem of finding the initial positions to deploy UAVs to provide service to ground personnel. In this work, we propose a greedy algorithm that finds a feasible solution that guarantees 100% coverage on any given map. We defined subareas of the map which do not need coverage as excluding zones. We considered both excluding zones and the connectivity constraints in the algorithm. By avoiding these zones and keeping all nodes connected to the network we can reduce the total number of UAVs needed to provide coverage without losing the communication capability. We show that the complexity of the algorithm is linear with respect to the input parameters. Simulation results show the behavior of our approach with different maps. We observe a convergence on the number of nodes needed when varying the input map.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="resources">Resources&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="resources/vtc_18fall.pdf">Manuscript&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="resources/vtc_18fall.pptx">Presentation&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="bibtex">Bibtex&lt;/h2>
&lt;div class="highlight">&lt;pre tabindex="0" style="color:#f8f8f2;background-color:#272822;-moz-tab-size:4;-o-tab-size:4;tab-size:4;">&lt;code class="language-latex" data-lang="latex">&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span>@inproceedings{regis2018unmanned,
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span> title={Unmanned Aerial Vehicles Positioning Scheme for First-responders in a Dynamic Area of Interest},
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span> author={Paulo Alexandre Regis, Amar Nath Patra, and Shamik Sengupta},
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span> year={2018},
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span> publisher={IEEE},
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span> address={Chicago, IL, USA},
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span> booktitle={2018 IEEE 88th Vehicular Technology Conference (VTC-Fall)},
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span>}
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;/code>&lt;/pre>&lt;/div></content></item><item><title>Distributed Adaptive Beam Nulling to Survive Against Jamming in 3 D Uav Mesh Networks</title><link>/publications/distributed-adaptive-beam-nulling-to-survive-against-jamming-in-3-d-uav-mesh-networks/</link><pubDate>Fri, 01 Jun 2018 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate><guid>/publications/distributed-adaptive-beam-nulling-to-survive-against-jamming-in-3-d-uav-mesh-networks/</guid><description>Abstract In the future generation mission-centric tactical network, 3D UAV mesh network will play a crucial role for its several advantages. However, any adversarial node with the 3D movement capability poses a significant threat to these networks as the adversary can position itself to attack the crucial links. An adaptive beamnulling antenna is used to spatially filter out signal coming from a certain direction that can maintain the links active without requiring additional spectrum.</description><content>&lt;h2 id="abstract">Abstract&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>In the future generation mission-centric tactical network, 3D UAV mesh network will play a crucial role for its several advantages. However, any adversarial node with the 3D movement capability poses a significant threat to these networks as the adversary can position itself to attack the crucial links. An adaptive beamnulling antenna is used to spatially filter out signal coming from a certain direction that can maintain the links active without requiring additional spectrum. However, determining the beamnull region is very challenging for jammer with mobility. This paper presents a distributed mechanism where nodes measure the jammer’s direction in a discrete interval and determine the optimal beamnull for the next interval. Kalman filter based tracking mechanism is used to estimate the most likely trajectory of the jammer from noisy observation of the jammer’s position. A beam null border is determined by calculating confidence region of jammer’s current and next position estimates. An optimization goal is presented to determine the optimal beam null that minimizes the number of deactivated links while maximizing the higher value of confidence for keeping the jammer inside the null. The framework works in the physical layer and can work with any upper layer protocol. The survivability of a 3D mesh network with a mobile jammer is studied through simulation that validates an 96.65% reduction in the number of jammed nodes.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="resources">Resources&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="resources/comnet_18.pdf">Manuscript&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="bibtex">Bibtex&lt;/h2>
&lt;div class="highlight">&lt;pre tabindex="0" style="color:#f8f8f2;background-color:#272822;-moz-tab-size:4;-o-tab-size:4;tab-size:4;">&lt;code class="language-latex" data-lang="latex">&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span>@article{bhunia2018distributed,
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span> title={Distributed Adaptive Beam Nulling to Survive Against Jamming in 3D UAV Mesh Networks},
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span> author={Suman Bhunia, Paulo Alexandre Regis, and Shamik Sengupta},
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span> year={2018},
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span> month={June},
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span> doi={10.1016/j.comnet.2018.03.011},
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span> journal={Elsevier Computer Networks},
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span>}
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;/code>&lt;/pre>&lt;/div></content></item><item><title>Distributed Split Path Routing Strategy for Multi Hop Mesh Networks</title><link>/publications/distributed-split-path-routing-strategy-for-multi-hop-mesh-networks/</link><pubDate>Sun, 01 Oct 2017 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate><guid>/publications/distributed-split-path-routing-strategy-for-multi-hop-mesh-networks/</guid><description>Abstract The concept of mesh networks brings many challenges to the research community when designing such system. In this paper, we propose a new routing model to account for the link utilization between nodes, as well as the remaining energy left in each node. The framework, called Distributed Split-path, is implemented on top of the Optimized Link-State Routing (OLSR) protocol. We demonstrate the improvement our proposed scheme offers to the longevity of the network while maintaining similar performance as the original OLSR protocol.</description><content>&lt;h1 id="abstract">Abstract&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>The concept of mesh networks brings many challenges to the research community when designing such system. In this paper, we propose a new routing model to account for the link utilization between nodes, as well as the remaining energy left in each node. The framework, called Distributed Split-path, is implemented on top of the Optimized Link-State Routing (OLSR) protocol. We demonstrate the improvement our proposed scheme offers to the longevity of the network while maintaining similar performance as the original OLSR protocol. We devise a performance indicator to show in which cases our approach benefits the network system designer, depending on the priorities of the network application. Simulation results show that by allowing a trade-off in the performance, the new model outperforms current protocol.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="resources">Resources&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="resources/milcom_17.pdf">Manuscript&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="resources/milcom_17.pptx">Presentation&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="bibtex">Bibtex&lt;/h2>
&lt;div class="highlight">&lt;pre tabindex="0" style="color:#f8f8f2;background-color:#272822;-moz-tab-size:4;-o-tab-size:4;tab-size:4;">&lt;code class="language-latex" data-lang="latex">&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span>@inproceedings{regis2017distributed,
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span> title={Distributed split-path routing strategy for multi-hop mesh networks},
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span> author={Paulo Alexandre Regis, and Shamik Sengupta},
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span> year={2017},
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span> publisher={IEEE},
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span> address={Baltimore, MD, USA},
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span> booktitle={MILCOM 2017 - 2017 IEEE Military Communications Conference (MILCOM)},
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span>}
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;/code>&lt;/pre>&lt;/div></content></item><item><title>Multi Hop Mobile Wireless Mesh Network Testbed Development and Measurements</title><link>/publications/multi-hop-mobile-wireless-mesh-network-testbed-development-and-measurements/</link><pubDate>Tue, 01 Aug 2017 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate><guid>/publications/multi-hop-mobile-wireless-mesh-network-testbed-development-and-measurements/</guid><description>Abstract Mesh networks are envisioned to play a major role in the future of Smart-Cities and Internet of Things technologies, and can be a great ally in executing mission-centric tasks like search and rescue, and assist first responders. In this paper, we demonstrate the feasibility of development of a mobile mesh network testbed with the help of commercial-off-the-shelf (COTS) components and perform measurement tests in an indoor environment. We used open-source software to enable the testbed, such as Linux as the operating system, and Optimized Link State Routing (OLSR) protocol to enable the wireless mesh network.</description><content>&lt;h2 id="abstract">Abstract&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Mesh networks are envisioned to play a major role in the future of Smart-Cities and Internet of Things technologies, and can be a great ally in executing mission-centric tasks like search and rescue, and assist first responders. In this paper, we demonstrate the feasibility of development of a mobile mesh network testbed with the help of commercial-off-the-shelf (COTS) components and perform measurement tests in an indoor environment. We used open-source software to enable the testbed, such as Linux as the operating system, and Optimized Link State Routing (OLSR) protocol to enable the wireless mesh network. The physical components include open-source hardware like Raspberry Pi computers, and mobility is enabled through the use of a mobile robot Pioneer 3. We evaluate the network in various scenarios, first establishing benchmark measurement in a stationary setup, and then comparing with a mobile variation.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="resources">Resources&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="resources/rroij_17.pdf">Manuscript&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="bibtex">Bibtex&lt;/h2>
&lt;div class="highlight">&lt;pre tabindex="0" style="color:#f8f8f2;background-color:#272822;-moz-tab-size:4;-o-tab-size:4;tab-size:4;">&lt;code class="language-latex" data-lang="latex">&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span>@article{regis2017multi-hop,
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span> title={Multi-hop Mobile Wireless Mesh Network Testbed Development and Measurements},
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span> author={Paulo Alexandre Regis, Cayler Miley, and Shamik Sengupta},
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span> year={2017},
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span> month={August},
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span> journal={IJIRCCE International Journal of Innovative Research in Computer and Communication Engineering},
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span>}
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;/code>&lt;/pre>&lt;/div></content></item><item><title>Enhancing Performance and Longevity of Multi Radio Multi Channel Het Nets Through Dynamic Path Assignment</title><link>/publications/enhancing-performance-and-longevity-of-multi-radio-multi-channel-het-nets-through-dynamic-path-assignment/</link><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2017 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate><guid>/publications/enhancing-performance-and-longevity-of-multi-radio-multi-channel-het-nets-through-dynamic-path-assignment/</guid><description>Abstract In this paper, we present a novel approach to assign paths to data streams in a mission-centric heterogeneous wireless mesh network where nodes have multi-channel radio interfaces. Different than conventional packet-switching routing, our approach assigns the paths using a link utility based on sub-topologies of non-orthogonal frequencies. We use a graph coloring algorithm to calculate the utility of each link. We then propose two path assignment strategies: (i) single path, where each data stream traverse a unique path, and (ii) split-path, where the flows can be divided into multiple paths.</description><content>&lt;h2 id="abstract">Abstract&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>In this paper, we present a novel approach to assign paths to data streams in a mission-centric heterogeneous wireless mesh network where nodes have multi-channel radio interfaces. Different than conventional packet-switching routing, our approach assigns the paths using a link utility based on sub-topologies of non-orthogonal frequencies. We use a graph coloring algorithm to calculate the utility of each link. We then propose two path assignment strategies: (i) single path, where each data stream traverse a unique path, and (ii) split-path, where the flows can be divided into multiple paths. Results show no best strategy fits all scenarios. Instead, in different situations, different algorithms are better suited.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="resources">Resources&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="resources/icnc_17.pdf">Manuscript&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="resources/icnc_17.pptx">Presentation&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="bibtex">Bibtex&lt;/h2>
&lt;div class="highlight">&lt;pre tabindex="0" style="color:#f8f8f2;background-color:#272822;-moz-tab-size:4;-o-tab-size:4;tab-size:4;">&lt;code class="language-latex" data-lang="latex">&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span>@inproceedings{regis2017enhancing,
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span> title={Enhancing Performance and Longevity of Multi-radio Multi-channel HetNets through Dynamic Path-assignment},
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span> author={Paulo Alexandre Regis, Suman Bhunia, and Shamik Sengupta},
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span> year={2017},
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span> publisher={IEEE},
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span> address={Silicon Valley, USA},
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span> booktitle={2017 International Conference on Computing, Networking and Communications (ICNC)},
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span>}
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;/code>&lt;/pre>&lt;/div></content></item><item><title>Adaptive Beam Nulling in Multihop Ad Hoc Networks Against a Jammer in Motion</title><link>/publications/adaptive-beam-nulling-in-multihop-ad-hoc-networks-against-a-jammer-in-motion/</link><pubDate>Tue, 01 Nov 2016 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate><guid>/publications/adaptive-beam-nulling-in-multihop-ad-hoc-networks-against-a-jammer-in-motion/</guid><description>Abstract In multihop ad hoc networks, a jammer can drastically disrupt the flow of information by intentionally interfering with links between a subset of nodes. The impact of such attacks can escalate when the jammer is moving. As a countermeasure for such attacks, adaptive beam-forming techniques can be employed for spatial filtering of the jamming signal. This paper investigates the performance of adaptive beam nulling as a mitigation technique against jamming attacks in multihop ad hoc networks.</description><content>&lt;h2 id="abstract">Abstract&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>In multihop ad hoc networks, a jammer can drastically disrupt the flow of information by intentionally interfering with links between a subset of nodes. The impact of such attacks can escalate when the jammer is moving. As a countermeasure for such attacks, adaptive beam-forming techniques can be employed for spatial filtering of the jamming signal. This paper investigates the performance of adaptive beam nulling as a mitigation technique against jamming attacks in multihop ad hoc networks. Considering a moving jammer, a distributed beam nulling framework is proposed. The framework uses periodic measurements of the RF environment to detect direction of arrival (DoA) of jamming signal and suppresses the signals arriving from the current and predicted locations of the jammer. Also, in the calculation of the nulled region, this framework considers and counters the effects of randomness in the mobility of the jammer, as well as errors in beam nulling and DoA measurements. Survivability of links and connectivity in such scenarios are studied by simulating various node distributions and different mobility patterns of the attacker. Also, the impact of errors in the estimation of DoA and beam-forming on the overall network performance is also examined. In comparison with an omnidirectional configuration, results indicate a 57.27% improvement in connectivity under jamming when the proposed framework is applied.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="resources">Resources&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="resources/comnet_16.pdf">Manuscript&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="bibtex">Bibtex&lt;/h2>
&lt;div class="highlight">&lt;pre tabindex="0" style="color:#f8f8f2;background-color:#272822;-moz-tab-size:4;-o-tab-size:4;tab-size:4;">&lt;code class="language-latex" data-lang="latex">&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span>@article{bhunia2016adaptive,
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span> title={Adaptive Beam Nulling in Multihop Ad Hoc Networks Against a Jammer in Motion},
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span> author={Suman Bhunia, Vahid Behzadan, Paulo Alexandre Regis, and Shamik Sengupta},
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span> year={2016},
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span> month={November},
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span> doi={10.1016/j.comnet.2016.06.030},
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span> journal={Elsevier Computer Networks},
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span>}
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;/code>&lt;/pre>&lt;/div></content></item><item><title>Implementation of 3D Obstacle Compliant Mobility Models for Uav Networks in ns-3</title><link>/publications/implementation-of-3-d-obstacle-compliant-mobility-models-for-uav-networks-in-ns-3/</link><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jun 2016 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate><guid>/publications/implementation-of-3-d-obstacle-compliant-mobility-models-for-uav-networks-in-ns-3/</guid><description>Abstract UAV networks are envisioned to play a crucial role in the future generations of wireless networks. The mechanical degrees of freedom in the movement of UAVs provides various advantages for tactical and civilian applications. Due to the high cost of failures in system-based tests, initial analysis and refinement of designs and algorithms for UAV applications are performed through rigorous simulations. Current trend of UAV specific simulators is mainly biased towards the mechanical properties of flying.</description><content>&lt;h2 id="abstract">Abstract&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>UAV networks are envisioned to play a crucial role in the future generations of wireless networks. The mechanical degrees of freedom in the movement of UAVs provides various advantages for tactical and civilian applications. Due to the high cost of failures in system-based tests, initial analysis and refinement of designs and algorithms for UAV applications are performed through rigorous simulations. Current trend of UAV specific simulators is mainly biased towards the mechanical properties of flying. For network-centric simulations, the intended measurements on the performance of protocols in mobile scenarios are conventionally captured from general-purpose network simulators, which are not natively equipped with comprehensive models for 3D movements of UAVs. To facilitate such simulations for UAV systems, this paper presents different mobility models for emulation of the movement of a UAV. Detailed description of three mobility models (random walk, random direction, and Gauss-Markov) are presented, and their associated movement patterns are characterized. This characterization is further extended by considering the effect of large obstacles on movement patterns of nodes following the three models. The mobility models are prepared as open-source add-ons for ns-3 network simulator.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="resources">Resources&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="resources/wns3_16.pdf">Manuscript&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="resources/wns3_16.pptx">Presentation&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;div class="block 500">
&lt;iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/ACmmxe3vPjo" allowfullscreen title="Random direction mobility model in 3D with obstacle using ns-3">&lt;/iframe>
&lt;/div>
&lt;div class="500">
&lt;iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/zJocofWmodg" allowfullscreen title="Gauss-Markov mobility model in 3D with obstacle using ns-3">&lt;/iframe>
&lt;/div>
&lt;div class="500">
&lt;iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/1m8X7NGdP3w" allowfullscreen title="Random walk (time mode) mobility model in 3D with obstacle using ns-3">&lt;/iframe>
&lt;/div>
&lt;div class="500">
&lt;iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/MFCymLmYj6U" allowfullscreen title="Random walk (distance mode) mobility model in 3D with obstacle using ns-3">&lt;/iframe>
&lt;/div>
&lt;h1 id="bibtex">Bibtex&lt;/h1>
&lt;div class="highlight">&lt;pre tabindex="0" style="color:#f8f8f2;background-color:#272822;-moz-tab-size:4;-o-tab-size:4;tab-size:4;">&lt;code class="language-latex" data-lang="latex">&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span>@inproceedings{regis2016implementation,
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span> title={Implementation of 3D Obstacle Compliant Mobility Models for UAV networks in ns-3},
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span> author={Paulo Alexandre Regis, Suman Bhunia, and Shamik Sengupta},
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span> year={2016},
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span> publisher={ACM},
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span> address={Seattle, WA, USA},
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span> booktitle={None},
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span>}
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;/code>&lt;/pre>&lt;/div></content></item><item><title>Performance of Adaptive Beam Nulling in Multihop Ad Hoc Networks Under Jamming</title><link>/publications/performance-of-adaptive-beam-nulling-in-multihop-ad-hoc-networks-under-jamming/</link><pubDate>Sat, 01 Aug 2015 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate><guid>/publications/performance-of-adaptive-beam-nulling-in-multihop-ad-hoc-networks-under-jamming/</guid><description>Abstract In a multihop ad hoc network, end-to-end data transmissions traverse through multiple inter-node wireless links. A jammer can disrupt the entire data transfer of a network by intentionally interfering with links between a subset of nodes. The impact of such attacks is escalated when the jammer is moving. While the majority of current ad hoc protocols consider omnidirectional transmission and reception, adaptive antennas can be utilized for spatial filtering of the jamming signal.</description><content>&lt;h2 id="abstract">Abstract&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>In a multihop ad hoc network, end-to-end data transmissions traverse through multiple inter-node wireless links. A jammer can disrupt the entire data transfer of a network by intentionally interfering with links between a subset of nodes. The impact of such attacks is escalated when the jammer is moving. While the majority of current ad hoc protocols consider omnidirectional transmission and reception, adaptive antennas can be utilized for spatial filtering of the jamming signal. This paper investigates the performance of employing adaptive beam nulling as a mitigation technique against jamming attacks in multihop ad hoc networks. Considering a moving jammer, the survivability of links and connectivity in such networks are studied by simulating various node distributions and different mobility patterns of the attacker. In addition, the impact of errors in estimation of direction of arrival and beamforming on the overall network performance are also examined. The results indicate a significant improvement in retaining connectivity under jamming when adaptive beam nulling is applied.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="resources">Resources&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="resources/css_15.pdf">Manuscript&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="resources/css_15.pptx">Presentation&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="bibtex">Bibtex&lt;/h2>
&lt;div class="highlight">&lt;pre tabindex="0" style="color:#f8f8f2;background-color:#272822;-moz-tab-size:4;-o-tab-size:4;tab-size:4;">&lt;code class="language-latex" data-lang="latex">&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span>@inproceedings{bhunia2015performance,
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span> title={Performance of Adaptive Beam Nulling in Multihop Ad-Hoc networks under Jamming},
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span> author={Suman Bhunia, Vahid Behzadan, Paulo Alexandre Regis, and Shamik Sengupta},
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span> year={2015},
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span> publisher={IEEE},
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span> address={New York, NY, USA},
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span> booktitle={2015 IEEE 17th International Conference on High Performance Computing and Communications, 2015 IEEE 7th International Symposium on Cyberspace Safety and Security, and 2015 IEEE 12th International Conference on Embedded Software and Systems},
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span style="display:flex;">&lt;span>}
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;/code>&lt;/pre>&lt;/div></content></item></channel></rss>